

MERT KAYA

+90 530-831-59-46

e-mail: mertkayacs@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mertkayaturkey/

https://github.com/mertkayacs

www.mertkayacs.com

INTRODUCTION

Hi! My name is Mert KAYA. I am 24 years old. I have graduated from TOBB ETU Computer Engineering Department at November 2021. I am very passionate about coding, developing software and AI. I love solving problems and working hard until the current problem is solved.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science (3 Year Program)

Aug. 2022 - Contd

International University of Applied Sciences Berlin

(Remote)Berlin, Germany

Bachelors Degree of Computer Science / Computer Engineering

Sep. 2016 – Nov. 2021

TOBB University of Economics and Technology

Ankara, Turkey

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer Dec 2021 – Sept 2022.
Alictus Ankara, Turkey

- Single handedly coded transferred every project into cloud. Worked with Cloud, Golang, SQL, Azure, Bash. Created a new Cloud VM which handles daily pipelines for each data process in company. Worked as a data engineer too in the meantime. Since Alictus has been sold to SciPlay for 100M\$ + 200\$, I have decided that I would like to work on a more project based software companies since my role has a chance to become more of a maintenance based.
- Worked with golang, docker, azure, databricks, sql, python.

Software Engineering Internship (Long Term - Paid) SimBT A.S.	Sep 2021 – Dec 2021. Ankara, Turkey
Software Development - Game Development Internship Roar Games Studio	Apr 2021 – Sep 2021 Ankara, Turkey
Software Engineering Internship (Long Term - Paid) BiSoft A.S	Sep 2020 – Dec 2020 Ankara, Turkey
Software Engineering Internship (Long Term - Paid) SimBT A.S.	Sep 2019 – Dec 2019 Ankara, Turkey

LANGUAGES:

• Turkish: Native

• English: C2 level (Supported by an IELTS UKVI Academic)

• German: A2 level

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH / SKILLS / CERTIFICATIONS / HOBBIES

Find all of the above in: http://www.mertkayacs.com. and in: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mertkayaturkey/.